# MAX BOLGER.

——— **♀** Minneapolis, MN

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Data scientist with 3+ years of experience in developing, automating, and scaling machine learning models in fastpaced, technical environments. Emphasizing clean, readable code, efficient, vectorized processes, and transparent, accessible documentation. Aspiring to develop data pipelines leveraging state of the art software to enhance businesses.

### **SKILLS**

Proficient In Python, SQL, R, Spreadsheet Software, Conda, Spark, Tableau

**Technical Skills** Data Science, Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Web Scraping,

A/B Testing, Big Data, Version Control, Statistics, Binomial and Poisson Processes

Soft Skills Problem Solving, Emotional Intelligence, Dependability, Determination, Communication

#### EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist May 2021 - Present Minneapolis, MN

Optum - subsidary of UnitedHealth Group

• Sole developer, maintainer, and owner of a family of 6 different fully-automated, production-level machine learning models that predict scheduling probabilities for HouseCalls members in different capacities by using a data science stack of python (pandas, scikit-learn, sqlalchemy, and more), SQL, and batch scripting, all version controlled by conda

- Sole developer, maintainer, and owner of a fully-automated, production-level machine learning model that predicts readmission probabilities for HouseCalls members by using a data science stack of python (pandas, scikitlearn, sqlalchemy, and more), SQL, and batch scripting, all version controlled by conda
- Improved a variety of out-dated machine learning models yielding accuracy increases of up to 7% and propensity calibration tenfold via model selection and hyperparameter optimization, cleaning the codebase to abide by python's PEP8 style guide, and increasing computational efficiency using vectorized operations

## **Data Science Associate**

Dec 2019 - May 2021

Hamline University Marketing Analytics Clinic (HUMAC)

St. Paul. MN

• Led the data science team in developing business solutions for Twin Cities businesses AmeriSave Mortgage and Two Bettys Green Cleaning using python to conduct data-driven analysis such as predicting customer retention

# Freelance Data Scientist

Dec 2020 - Present

- Establish The Run: Used streamlit to develop a web app UI for the company to display proprietary content to subscribers
- Occupy Fantasy: Used python to develop a script that parses and analyzes sports betting information and pre-processes it to deliver actionable advice to subscribers

#### PROJECTS

WNBA Player Dashboard Developed a streamlit dashboard that visualizes a variety of statistics - including proprietary metrics leveraging my WNBA shot probability machine learning model - for any of the 990 WNBA players to attempt a shot between 1996-2021. View it here!

Voting Classifier App Developed a streamlit web app that visualizes decision boundaries for a scikit-learn voting classifier and the models it consists of using the Palmer Penguins dataset. View it here!

### **EDUCATION**

B.S. Computational Data Science, Hamline University

2018-2022